ILGWU. David Melman papers, 5780/152
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- ILGWU Convention: Travel Arrangements, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Memo to regional directors warning of inconvenience in flight arrangements due to strike with Eastern Airlines, notes ILG contribution to strike fund; correspondence and travel insurance policy certificate; memos re logistics of arrivals and departures
- ILGWU Convention: Videos, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  Schedule of videos shown on in-house hotel channel, including "Triangle Fire," "A. Philip Randolph: Portrait in Black," "Wrath of Grapes"; memo requesting copies of eight taped segments from convention, including speech by NY Gov. Mario Cuomo; list of 39 tape segments; proposal, letter of agreement, and draft scripts of video commissioned for convention, "On the Move," and cover letter from Sheridan Elson Communications, Inc.; proposal from Day's Work Productions (division of Abernathy & Mitchell) with critical handwritten notes; memo from Susan Cowell suggesting themes for videos, endorsing proposal by the Kamber Group (attached)
- ILGWU Convention: Workshops, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Memo, descriptions, and sign-up sheets for workshops: benefits, pre-retirement, health and safety, international solidarity, and organizing (Spanish, Chinese, English); agenda outline, "Meeting on Exhibits and Workshops"
- ILGWU Convention: Post Convention Commentary, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  Minutes, "Summary of Post-Convention Meeting," July 24, 1989, including reactions to reports and suggestions for changes (increasing number of secretaries, instituting shift system, guaranteeing time off), cost-cutting, decision to try to find another hotel for 1992 convention; report on experience of secretarial pool; report on experience of chorus; list of convention expenses; post-convention letters to hotel director of sales, and from hotel president and CEO, re poor physical conditions at hotel; handwritten letter from delegate, in Spanish, and English translation, expressing appreciation for translation services; letter from Canadian District Council expressing appreciation for financial assistance; letter from lawyer expressing satisfaction with convention; letter from musician Malcolm Dodds expressing appreciation for title of Honorary Vice President
- ILGWU Convention: Planning, Logistics, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  Minutes of planning meetings, "Future Notes for 1989 Convention," checklist of logistics for arrival and departure, summary of invoices, correspondence; list of vice presidents, NYC managers and directors, committees; convention week agenda
- ILGWU Convention Call, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  Drafts of letters to locals announcing convention, outlining procedure for election of delegates; 27 subsequent letters instructing actions for next stages, delegate per diems, travel arrangements; credential certificate forms; newspaper clippings re current and previous convention calls; planning timetables
- ILGWU Convention: Letter of Support, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  Letters and mailgrams from the U.S. Department of Labor (Secretary William Brock), Communication Workers of America, United Garment Workers of America, Union Label & Service Trades Department AFL-CIO, and the Workmen's Circle Home and Infirmary for the Aged.
- ILGWU Convention: Hotel Diplomat Contract and Correspondence, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  Delegate guide for 1983 convention, with note to hotel sales manager from Wilbur Daniels to bring it up to date; delegate guide for 1986 convention; letters from convention services provider Morton Grebelsky (Regal Services) confirming terms of agreement; correspondence re gratuities; contracts with Diplomat Hotel
- ILGWU Convention: Printed Proceeding, Convention Daily, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  Correspondence re photographer Bert Berinsky; copies of CONVENTION DAILY, daily newsletter distributed at convention; contact sheet of photographs for newsletter (originals held in Kheel photo archives); partial official printed proceedings (galley proofs, some with editing)
- ILGWU Convention: Signage, Art, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  Correspondence re banner suggestions, checklist of signs; names of committees; list of slogans used at 1983 convention; mock-ups of artwork for signs and cover of General Executive Board report
- ILGWU Convention: Songs, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  "Sing-A-Long…with the ILGWU" 1986 convention songbook; UAW songbook, 1984, with memo to Wilbur Daniels; memo suggesting Bruce Springsteen be invited to perform a version of "Born in the USA" ("Made in the USA"), noting his support for working people; typed lyrics to other songs, commemorating Triangle fire, praising outgoing president Sol Chaikin; itemized invoices for Malcolm Dodds Music
- ILGWU Convention: Speakers Invited, Correspondence, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  List of guest speakers at 1977, 1980, 1983 conventions; list of speakers at other labor union (IUE, UAW, AFT) recent conventions; suggestions for speakers from ILG officers; declined invitations from NY Gov. Mario Cuomo; San Antonio, TX, mayor Cisneros; invitation to, but no reply from, Sen. Edward Kennedy; accepted invitations from AFL-CIO pres. Lane Kirkland; Shirley Carr, pres. Canadian Labour Congress; Sen. Hollings; South African labor activist Emma Mashinini, several clergy; introductions/biographies of speakers; press release re speakers
- ILGWU Convention: Staff, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  Lists of secretarial and other staff working the convention; memos
- ILGWU Convention: Vendors, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  Sample of ILGWU button to be used at convention; corresp. re nonpayment dispute between entertainment providers Wildlife Music and Manhattan Repertory Company; terms of agreement with Convention & Group Travel Associates; press kit of the Building and Construction Trades Department (AFL-CIO); corresp. with Burrell Actuations re promotional items with logo "Crafted with Pride in U.S.A."; corresp. with Carroll & Graf Publishers re mass copies of THE TRIANGLE FIRE by Leon Stern; with Memorial Bibles, an all-union shop; with Medical Personnel Pool re providing nursing services; copies of CONVENTION UNITY, the daily convention publication of ACTWU, which held convention at Diplomat Hotel in 1984
- ILGWU Convention: Election Notices, Canada, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  Winnipeg, Manitoba
- ILGWU Convention: Election Notices, Central States, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  Arkansas, Missouri, Mississippi, Oklahoma, Texas
- ILGWU Convention: Election Notices, Eastern PA, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  Philadelphia¬-South Jersey District Council; Allentown
- ILGWU Convention: Election Notices, Midwest, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  Illinois, Iowa, Indiana, Michigan
- ILGWU Convention: Election Notices, New England, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  Connecticut, Massachusetts, Vermont
- ILGWU Convention: Election Notices, New Jersey, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- ILGWU Convention: Election Notices, New York City, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- ILGWU Convention: Election Notices, New York State (excluding NYC), 1986 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  Upstate New York, Nassau-Suffolk, Lower Hudson District Councils
- ILGWU Convention: Election Notices, Northeast Department, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  Central Pennsylvania, Ohio
- ILGWU Convention: Election Notices, Puerto Rico, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- ILGWU Convention: Election Notes, Southeast, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  N. Carolina, S. Carolina, Mississippi, Alabama, Georgia, Florida
- ILGWU Convention: Election Notices, Upper South, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  Virginia, Maryland, West Virginia, Kentucky
- ILGWU Convention: Election Notices, Western States, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  Los Angeles and San Francisco, California
- ILGWU Convention: Election Returns, Canada, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  notes some problems
- ILGWU Convention: Election Returns, Central States, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- ILGWU Convention: Election Returns, Midwest, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- ILGWU Convention: Election Returns, New England, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- ILGWU Convention: Election Returns, New Jersey, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  Letter from manager of Local 160 in Bayonne, NJ, appealing for financial assistance from New Jersey Region for delegates to attend
- ILGWU Convention: Election Returns, New York State, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- ILGWU Convention: Election Returns, New York City, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- ILGWU Convention: Election Returns, Northeast, Western PA, Ohio Department, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- ILGWU Convention: Election Returns, Philadelphia-South Jersey District, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  Minutes of election meetings of various locals
- ILGWU Convention: Election Returns, Puerto Rico, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- ILGWU Convention: Election Returns, Southeast, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  Notes several locals that have gone out of existence
- ILGWU Convention: Election Returns, Upper South, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- ILGWU Convention: Election Returns, Western States, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- ILGWU Convention: Delegates, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  Comparison of delegate numbers by local for 1983 convention and 1986 convention; correspondence re various problems; per diem allowances; census of locals in 1984 and 1985 with delegate allocation entitlement; memos re appointment of head sergeant-at-arms; computer printouts of delegates, sergeants-at-arms, and guests attending
- ILGWU Convention: Delegates, Canadian, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  Correspondence re problems with delegates; draft of section of report pertaining to Canada; instructions for election procedures in French and Spanish
- ILGWU Convention: Retirees and Guests, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  Drafts of form-letter invitations to retired members; individual letters from retired members; lists of retired vice presidents and widows; list of retired staff living in Florida; letter from Florida Retiree Services Department to Social Security Administration requesting display re programs; memos from Retiree Services Department re expanded sessions and events program for retirees at convention, insurance coverage; correspondence and contract re on-site nurse, emergency medical treatment; script, "In Search of…the ILG Retiree"; correspondence re guests
- ILGWU Convention: Committee Officers and Staff, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  Recommendations for committee assignments from various locals; lists from 1983 convention
- ILGWU Convention: Executive Officer Reports, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  Drafts of General Executive Board report, drafts of speech by Irwin Solomon; draft of Executive Vice President's report (Wilbur Daniels); printed bios of Wilbur Daniels (1977, 1983, 1985); financial report (Jay Mazur); script or transcript of President Chaikin's remarks between committee reports
- ILGWU Convention: Master Agreements Report, Wilbur Daniels, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  Printed summaries of terms with Jonathan Logan, Leslie Fay, Bobbie Brooks, Maidenform, Mode O'Day, 1980 and 1983; Bobbie Brooks and Leslie Fay master agreements, 1985; letter of agreement with the Puerto Rican Corset & Brassiere Association, 1980-83 and 1983-85; handwritten notes
- ILGWU Convention: Union Label Report, Wilbur Daniels, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  Several edited drafts
- ILGWU Convention: Executive Officer Elections, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  Script or transcript of proceedings/stage directions
- ILGWU Convention: Constitutional Amendments, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  Printed proposed amendments; settlement with Department of Labor re elimination of 5% rule for seconding nominations; correspondence with ILG's Canadian attorney critiquing the viability of the union's constitution under Canadian law; legal opinions by AFL-CIO and ILG attorneys re slate voting, associate membership category
- ILGWU Convention: Strike Benefits, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  Resolutions introduced at 1980 and 1983 conventions proposing raising the strike benefit (defeated); memo, 1985
- ILGWU Convention: Committee Reports [folder 1 of 2], 1986 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  List of 1986 Convention Decisions; Proposed Amendments to the Constitution; list of committee chairs; reports and recommendations of Resolutions Committee; Appeals; Credentials; Education; Finance; Workers' Benefits; Institutions and Social Welfare Programs; Imports; International Affairs; Law; Organizing; Rules; Social & Labor Legislation; Union Label; Work Standards Committees
- ILGWU Convention: Committee Reports [folder 2 of 2], 1986 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- ILGWU Convention: General, Planning, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  Checklist of logistics, memo re plans for press coverage
- ILGWU Convention: Convention Call, Timetable, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  Drafts of letters to locals announcing convention, outlining procedure for election of delegates; 1980 call; planning timetables
- ILGWU Convention: Committee Assignments, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  Recommendations for committee assignments from various locals; lists from 1980 convention; memo to Pres. Chaikin from Wilbur Daniels recommending increasing number of women as officers
- ILGWU Convention: Constitutional Amendments, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  Printed proposed amendments; printed constitution as adopted at 1980 convention; memo from Local 99 proposing decrease in number of vice presidents (original and copy with editing changes, including gender-neutral language); individual proposed amendments; 1982 memo to ILG attorney requesting review of constitutional provisions re election of general manager, reply with part of constitution of United Food & Commercial Workers International Union; 1983 memo from ILG attorney suggesting language banning ILG membership by members of the Communist Party, with cover memo from Wilbur Daniels noting it was decided not to so amend; 1983 memo from attorney advising clarification of Art. 13, re appealing elections
- ILGWU Convention: Delegates, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  Printed brochure, "Delegate's Guide to 38th ILGWU Convention" (1983); lists of sergeants-at-arms, delegates, and guests; official election return ballot for delegates; convention floor layout showing delegation seating arrangement; correspondence re per diem allowances; memo re number of delegates allotted per affiliate, noting actual number will be lower due to some locals going out of existence
- ILGWU Convention: Events and Entertainment, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  Contract & correspondence with performers; list of dinners, breakfasts, and cocktail receptions for various delegations
- ILGWU Convention: Exhibits and Archives, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  Correspondence with Dept. of Health & Human Services and others for exhibits; with ILG archivist; sketches
- ILGWU Convention: Guests and Retirees, Invitations, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  List of retired vice presidents and widows; computer printout of guests at 1980 convention; handwritten correspondence from retiree, declining invitation due to inability to find respite care for ailing wife; letter from ACTWU, Amalgamated Clothing & Textile Workers Union industrial department director, accepting invitation; letter from General Federation of Labor in Israel (Histadrut), accepting invitation
- ILGWU Convention: Hotel Contract and Correspondence, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  Contracts with Diplomat Hotel, correspondence; 1980 correspondence including memo from hotel executive vice president noting that they have been removed from boycott over Equal Rights Amendment, with attached resolution, Feb 20, 1980, that the City of Hollywood, FL, does not oppose ratification of the ERA
- ILGWU Convention: Lawyer's Conference, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  Memos
- ILGWU Convention: Printed Convention Daily, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  Copies of CONVENTION DAILY, daily newsletter distributed at convention, days 1-7
- ILGWU Convention: Resolutions, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  Three lists of resolutions: those adopted at convention, those requiring action by the ILG general office; and those referred to the General Executive Board (GEB); list, "Subjects not covered by resolutions received thus far"; signed ballots authorizing restructuring of affiliates in Ontario, Canada, copy of resolution; mailgrams to various locals urgently requesting submission of resolutions
- ILGWU Convention: Slogans, Signage, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  Memos requesting suggestions for slogans; lists of slogans
- ILGWU Convention: Songs, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  "Sing-A-Long…with the ILGWU" 1983 convention songbook, general songbook, songbook of the AFL-CIO Union Label and Service Trades Department; typed lyrics to other songs
- ILGWU Convention: Speakers, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  Correspondence with offices of invited speakers: Vice President Walter Mondale, Rep. Geraldine Ferraro (D.-N.Y.) (air fare reimbursement check), Zensen (Japanese Federation of Textile, Garment, Chemical, Distributive and Allied Industry Workers) president Tadanobu Usami; Rep. William Gray III (D.-Pa.); press release announcing speakers at convention
- ILGWU Convention: Speeches, Scripts, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  "Proposed Script: Advertising Report, ILGWU Convention 1983," re imports, union label, TV advertising; list of computer disk locations for documents; script formats of speech introductions for officers' reports (no substantive content)
- ILGWU Convention: Staff, Secretarial, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  Lists of secretarial staff working the convention; memos
- ILGWU Convention: Vendors, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  Correspondence & invoices from service providers for on-site nursing staff (Medical Personnel Pool); photography (Bert Berinsky); Total Audiovisual Services (includes script sequence); Malcolm Dodds Music, computer systems (Leader Data Processing)
- ILGWU Convention: Convention Call, Planning, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  Convention Call announcing convention to locals; outline of procedure for election of delegates; credential certificate forms, hotel reservation form; official return forms for elected delegates and alternates; list of joint boards, district councils, departments and their local unions; memo to all affiliates requesting resolutions; memo requesting banners; memo re per diem allowances for delegates and guests; memo discussing travel arrangements; memo to Florida local 415-475 requesting liquor order
- ILGWU Convention: Air Fares, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  Invoices and payments for airline tickets through Unitours for officials and invited guests
- ILGWU Convention: Census, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  Memo to locals with questionnaire re number of members employed in various trades; balance sheets showing net changes in membership, 12/31/73-12/31/76; delegate appropriation entitlements per local, comparison with 1974
- ILGWU Convention: Delegate Seating, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  Memos to individual regional directors by name re seating arrangements at convention for delegations; schematics of seating for 1977 & 74 conventions; list of locals and delegate counts for each
- ILGWU Convention: Delegate Seating, Banquet, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  List of invited guests (all international labor leaders); list of staff; list of attendees (locals and individuals); engraved invitation, seating chart showing delegations
- ILGWU Convention: Financial Report, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  Printed "1974-76 Financial and Statistical Report, International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, January 1, 1974 to December 31, 1976, submitted by Sol C. Chaikin, President, General Secretary-Treasurer, 36th Convention, Hollywood, Florida, May 27, 1977"; associated balance sheets, working draft of narrative; hand-annotated copy of 1974 financial report (with notation, "Notes for 1977 Convention")
- ILGWU Convention: Balance Sheets, General Office, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  General office balance sheets; convention worksheets; dues rates, 1975, NYC; total wages as per 941p, 1976, accounting notes; reserves reported to conventions, 1901-1976; membership census, 1902-1976; schedule of donations to organizations; staff disability fund, special assistance fund, staff retirement fund, and label promotion fund balance sheets
- ILGWU Convention: General Executive Board Report, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  Addenda to financial report
- ILGWU Convention: Hotel Bills and Correspondence, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  Letter from Mort Grebelsky, president of American Convention Services, thanking President Chaikin for using his firm; detailed 3-page list of Diplomat Hotel staff gratuities; correspondence with hotel personnel re logistics; invoices
- ILGWU Convention: Payroll, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  Payroll sheets for ILG officers and staff at convention
- ILGWU Convention: Staff, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  List of staff at convention (including sergeants-at-arms, credentials committee), expense reimbursements
- ILGWU Convention: Convention Call, Planning, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  Convention Call announcing convention to locals; outline of procedure for election of delegates; memo to all affiliates requesting resolutions; memo re per diem allowances for delegates and guests; list of retired officers, wives, and widows receiving invitations; letter to Miami Beach Nursing Services; memo from hotel sales manager re daily logistics, arrivals and departures
- ILGWU Convention: Census, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  Memo to locals with questionnaire re number of members employed in various trades; census distribution of membership totals by state, Canadian province, and Puerto Rico; delegate appropriation entitlements per local based on 1973 census, comparison with 1971; membership turnover for 1971, 1972, 1973; lists of new locals, locals out of existence, and locals merged, 1/1/71 – 12/31/73; note summarizing number of locals, total membership, and staff
- ILGWU Convention: Delegate Seating, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  List of locals and delegate counts for each; memo to individual regional directors by name re seating arrangements at convention for delegations; seating charts showing delegations and number of delegates; printed banquet ticket; invoice from Craftsmen Photo Company for convention floor plans
- ILGWU Convention: Financial Report, Accounting Carried over from 1971 Convention, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  Accounting proposals carried forward from 1971 convention: six-page memo from Wilbur Daniels, list of decisions by President Stulberg re how fund balances are reported (September 25, 1970); audit critique: "Comments on statement of receipts and disbursements"
- ILGWU Convention: Financial Report, Balance Sheets, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  Printed "Financial and Statistical Report, January 1, 1971 to December 31, 1973, International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, submitted by Sol C. Chaikin, General Secretary-Treasurer, Thirty-Fifth Convention, Miami Beach, Florida, May 31, 1974"; general office balance sheets; convention worksheets; schedule of donations to organizations; staff disability fund, special assistance fund, staff retirement fund, death benefit fund, and label promotion fund balance sheets
- ILGWU Convention: Financial Report, President Chaikin's Report, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  Photocopy of printed financial report, with hand notations and cover memo from Milton Spitz; "You may find the attached useful for your report to the convention."
- ILGWU Convention: Staff, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  Lists of staff (including sergeants-at-arms) at convention, bonus/expense reimbursements
- ILGWU Convention: Convention Call, Planning, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  Convention Call announcing convention to locals; call for election of delegates; memo re per diem, questioning tax implications of compensation for lost wages during convention; memos to committee chairs
- ILGWU Convention: Census, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  Balance sheets showing net changes in membership by local, 12/31/67-12/31/70; Central States census of locals, January 1, 1968
- ILGWU Convention: Delegates, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 3)